<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (Posts about hpe)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/hpe.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 17:52:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Adventures</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/new-adventures/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;section id="hello-suse"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hello SUSE!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the start of a new chapter for me - I started as an employee
of SUSE this morning. After 3.5 years (I had no idea it was that long) in HPE
the time came, and me, and the rest of the team I work with, along with the
Cloud Foundry team, and the OpenStack teams all moved en-mass to the new
company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really excited to work with SUSE, they really get open source, and do it
well. I think with the progression of IaaS / CaaS / PaaS in recent years, we
will end up with something like the linux kernel, and a few distros built
around core open source components like OpenStack, Kubernetes and Cloud Foundry
(or OpenShift).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SUSE has already shown they know how to do an enterprise distribution of
an open source product, and I am looking forward to seeing how we do it for
the future of compute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a feeling of wistfulness leaving HP(E) - we did some amazing things
there, and we had an amazing group of teams working closely to produce the best
products we could. Running services in the public cloud will always be a
highlight for me, and the level of freedom we were given to work upstream
allowed us to have great projects, not just for HPE customers but for the
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But alas, life is like a river, and the flow has sped up, carrying me into the
next adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Graham&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description><category>hpe</category><category>job</category><category>suse</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/new-adventures/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 18:20:13 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>