<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (Posts about openstack)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/openstack.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:13:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Open Infrastructure Project(s)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/new-open-infrastructure-projects/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="new-oip-open-infrastructure-projects"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New OIP (Open Infrastructure Projects)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a long running program, started in Sydney at the OpenStack Foundation Board
meeting, the OpenStack Foundation (&lt;abbr title="OpenStack Foundation"&gt;OSF&lt;/abbr&gt;) has added
the first new project to the Foundation under the
&lt;abbr title="Open Infrastructure Projects"&gt;OIP&lt;/abbr&gt; program - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://katacontainers.io/"&gt;Kata Containers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation board has laid out a set of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Governance/Foundation/OSFProjectConfirmationGuidelines"&gt;requirements&lt;/a&gt; for projects to meet
before they are fully "confirmed" into the foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fall under 5 broad areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus - does the project do something in an area the board has previously said is an area of interest. Also known as a Strategic Focus Area (SFA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governance - Does the project act democratically, and have they had a stable process for this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Practices - does the project follow the lead of other foundation projects with technical practices - CI, code review, documentation, bug management and security processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open-ness - Does the project abide by the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/four-opens/"&gt;four opens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activity - How many people use the project, and contribute to it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kata-containers"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kata Containers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/egernst"&gt;Eric Ernst&lt;/a&gt; from the Kata Architectural Committee gave a very in depth
overview of Kata and what they are doing in the container space. The slides
for this are available on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Vil7Px-KyjxrfjO4TT25hKRDb2O02_qmrn4RtFBq0d4/edit"&gt;Google Slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="focus"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Focus&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kata strives to solve a large, known problem in the container space, which is a
listed &lt;abbr title="Strategic Focus Area"&gt;SFA&lt;/abbr&gt; previously defined by the board. They
started as a pilot project in the foundation, with the merging of Intel and hyper.sh
IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many public cloud providers have had to write something like Kata for their operations,
and Kata aims to bring this security to the Open Source space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="governance"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Governance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kata governance is similar to the OpenStack Project governance - they have
contributors (ATCs), Maintainers (cores) and an Architecture Committee (TC).
There is no PTL role, but as a smaller project, that would be unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="best-practices"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Best Practices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kata is in a good place for this - they have CI on each PR, a good set of docs,
and a &lt;abbr title="Vulnerability Management Team"&gt;VMT&lt;/abbr&gt; that is very similar to the
OpenStack one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="open-ness"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Open-ness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They keep everything in open forums - they use Slack but also bridge the
conversations into channels on freenode, so people can use IRC to talk to them,
the use open Google Docs for specifications, and allow people to comment on
specs to feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have attended summits before, and reach out to related communities
(hypervisors and kubernetes were given as examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="activity"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Activity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an area I was initially concerned about - but the names and number of
users (in production and R&amp;amp;D / testing) looks like it is gaining a growing
community. As is to be expected, a lot of people fall into the "pre prod" / R&amp;amp;D
phase - this is a very new technology, with no current enterprise offerings
which would make companies start out slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;As a side note, if was an enterprise linux company, I would be pushing for us
to produce a Kata + Firecracker + Kubeless extension to their Containers
product ASAP, to beat the rest of the market. There is definite potential
for this to be a major product line for hybrid customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the presentation we moved to questions from the board to the Architecture
Committee - I have 2.5 pages of notes from this section, so I will not be
talking about every question asked here :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="questions"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-are-kata-and-openstack-integrating-and-using-each-other"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How are Kata and OpenStack integrating, and using each other?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zun is currently looking at integrating Kata as a container runtime, and
in the days since the board meeting I have seen mailing list posts on this, and
some people have been investigating Magnum as well. Currently there is no real
push from the Kata side, as they let end users drive features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-there-any-commercial-distribution-of-kata"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Is there any commercial distribution of Kata?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, no. There is interest from customers, but currently no distro has
provided support. SUSE / RedHat / Ubuntu have started to work on support in
the linux distros, but not on a product version yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most current users don't want a product version, they are happy to trail blaze
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-does-kata-work-with-the-kubernetes-community"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;How does Kata work with the Kubernetes community?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kata and kubernetes do end to end testing with CRI.O and containerd. As the CRI
is the interface, Kata has been (and is) involved in the development of that
standard, and has helped drive some of the features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, Alan Clark proposed the board vote on "Approving confirmation of
Kata Containers as a Open Infrastructure Project in the OpenStack Foundation."
This was seconded by Imad Sousou. Of the directors present, all bar one voted
in favor. Arkady Kanevsky abstained (based on a disagreement on the timing of
the vote, not on the substantive motion itself.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zuul"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Zuul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/community/members/profile/72/monty-taylor"&gt;Monty Taylor&lt;/a&gt; presented on behalf of the Zuul Maintainers. In true
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/four-opens/"&gt;four opens&lt;/a&gt; style, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://zuul-ci.org/confirmation/"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; was produced on gerrit and zuul itself
in the open for the community to comment on as it was being written :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a lot less notes on zuul, as I know the project, and in short it is
great. The users are a core part of the governance, and there are multiple
large installations outside of the OpenStack CI install. People use it to
test everything from kubernetes to network switches, which shows the level of
flexibility that is in place in the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Questions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I am not going to cover every single question, just the ones I thought
were interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="is-there-a-published-roadmap"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Is there a published roadmap?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - not in a traditional sense. The maintainers have a prioritised list of
features, that will get done as they get done (as soon as people show up to
write them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-does-the-zuul-need-from-the-openstack-foundation"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;What does the Zuul need from the OpenStack Foundation?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They need help with technical marketing (educating people about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; Zuul
works, and why it is such a good thing), and outreach. For outreach,  Zuul
has been seen as an "OpenStack" only thing, and letting people know they can use
it without OpenStack would be a good thing for the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was noted there has been cases where people adopted Zuul, and then decided
they wanted to bring in OpenStack to help manage the pool of CI VMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="licenses-does-the-board-need-to-pass-a-specific-exception-for-the-gplv3-sections"&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Licenses - does the board need to pass a specific exception for the GPLv3 sections?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - the board has already approved the use of GPLv3 in certain areas of the
Zuul code base (mainly around ansible integrations, but also in the zuul-preview
service). However the board got concerned, and decided to wait until the meeting
in Denver to approve Zuul, and the text of any license exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="by-laws-update"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;By Laws Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
4.16 Open Meetings and Records. Except as necessary to protect attorney-client
privilege, sensitive personnel information, discuss the candidacy of
potential Gold Member and Platinum Members, &lt;em&gt;and discuss the review and
approval of Open Infrastructure Projects,&lt;/em&gt; the Board of Directors shall:
(i) permit observation of its meetings by Members via remote teleconference or
other electronic means, and (ii) publish the Board of Directors minutes and
make available to any Member on request other information and records of the
Foundation as required by Delaware Corporate Law.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—New OpenStack Foundation By-Laws (change in italics)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a previous meeting, the board expressed a wish to be able to talk about adding
a project in an executive session. The above change was posted to the foundation
mailing list a week or so before the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a quote on the agenda that said "Feedback from the community is
amenable to the addition w/some requests for word changes", which was
unfortunately not quite true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had replied to the thread a day or two after it was sent, but it seems most
directors do not read the &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:foundation@lists.openstack.org"&gt;foundation@lists.openstack.org&lt;/a&gt; mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still not sure what could be required for an executive session that
is not covered by "sensitive personnel information" that would require
this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, for me, this looks like we are not abiding by our own ethos
of the Four Opens - I do understand if there is personel issues with a
potential project, we would want to have it discussed behind closed
doors, but everything else should be in the open. If the project
that is about to be included has large enough personnel issues that
they could cause issues for its inclusion in the foundation, there
is a very high chance that they are going to fail some of the
confirmation guidelines, and that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; something the community
should have visibility into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even from an optics perspective - the board deciding to include or
not include a project behind closed doors is not something that
is representative of the OpenStack community, and not something
I think the community should be supporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/foundation/2019-April/002749.html"&gt;http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/foundation/2019-April/002749.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After sending this there was a discussion in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://eavesdrop.openstack.org/irclogs/%23openstack-tc/%23openstack-tc.2019-04-05.log.html#t2019-04-05T15:20:47"&gt;#openstack-tc&lt;/a&gt; channel about
the change. This should show that the community is not "generally amenable" to
the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I cannot see the reason for this change - I do not want to
oversimplify this, but if there is not a &lt;strong&gt;legal restriction&lt;/strong&gt; for a director to
say why they are for or against a project being included, and the director will
only say if they support or do not support a project in an executive session,
they need to examine their reasons for being there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a train of thought that we should trust our elected board members -
which I do - I remember to trust but verify. If there was a discussion at an
executive session, they would not be able to raise a flag to the community
that something was amiss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting, that the line about Gold and Platinum members was added
as an amendment to the by-laws, and now the default route that a member goes
though is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation from the prospective member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executive Session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote appears out of the discussion in that session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this what we want to have when we are including new project teams in our
community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my question to the directors would be this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you want to add this to the by-laws? When do you see it being used?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be at the board meeting in Denver, and I look forward to hearing the
reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>board</category><category>foundation</category><category>OIP</category><category>openstack</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/new-open-infrastructure-projects/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:03:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TC Nomination - Rocky Cycle</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/me.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am submitting my candidacy for the OpenStack Technical Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been contributing to OpenStack since the Havana cycle &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/#id7" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/#id8" id="id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;, mainly
in Designate. I have also been involved with the TC, and its meetings since
Designate applied for incubation all the way back in Atlanta (the first time
we were there).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last 6 months I have become more involved in the TC, and have been
an active contributor to TC discussions (both on IRC and in person) and
governance &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/#id9" id="id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been PTL for Designate for Mitaka, Newton, Ocata, Queens and Rocky
cycles, and a core for a longer period. I believe my experience working in a
younger, smaller project within OpenStack is a benefit. Along with the
experience of working on software as an end user of OpenStack I can help us
ensure the Technical Committee is mindful of the unique challenges these
projects and users can face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>elections</category><category>openstack</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination-rocky/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 14:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dublin PTG Summary</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/dublin-ptg-summary/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DXItoxEW4AAqaxV.jpg:medium"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DXItoxEW4AAqaxV.jpg:large" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DXItoxEW4AAqaxV.jpg:large"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not getting on a plane was a nice change for an OpenStack event :) - especially
as it looks like I would not have made it home for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cross-project-days-monday-tuesday"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cross Project Days (Monday / Tuesday)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days are where I think the major value of the PTG is. The cross project
days feel like the Summit of old, with more time for topics, and less running
around a conference centre trying to cram 2 weeks worth of talks / developer
sessions, and other meetings into a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="unified-limits-olso-limits-keystone-stored-limit-data"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Unified Limits / olso.limits / keystone stored limit data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up for me was the keystone based limits API for unifying quota data in
keystone. It was decided to create oslo.limts (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/550491/"&gt;olso.limits repo&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2018-March/128175.html"&gt;olso.limits spec&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/unified-limits-rocky-ptg"&gt;oslo.limits etherpad&lt;/a&gt;). The keystone team already
created a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developer.openstack.org/api-ref/identity/v3/index.html#unified-limits"&gt;keystone-limits-api&lt;/a&gt; that is currently experimental, and the
feeling in the room was that we should try and implement it using a new oslo
library to find where changes need to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The migration procedure was discussed, and how we (the services) would need to
run multiple quota systems for quite a few cycles, due to partial upgrades
that happen in OpenStack. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/dublin-ptg-summary/#id2" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Possible implementations were discussed, and
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/unified-limits-rocky-ptg"&gt;oslo.limits etherpad&lt;/a&gt; has a good overview of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="olso-healthcheck"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;olso.healthcheck&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an idea that I have been very interested in since it was discussed in
Sydney. We actually had 3 sessions on this in Dublin, across 3 different cross
project rooms - API-SIG, Oslo and Self Healing SIG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, most people were receptive - the commentary is that the spec is too
wordy, and contains my favorite description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
It feels like OpenStack, but not really in a good way.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After listening to feedback, and talking offline to a few people I think I have
a handle on where the issues are, and I think I have a rough spec I can work flesh
out over the next few days. I think I will just start writing code at that
point as well - I think with a more concrete example it could help clear up
issues for people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="edge-computing"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Edge Computing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stopped by the Edge room on the Tuesday to listen in on the discussion.
Personally, I really think this group needs to stop bikesheding on, well,
everything, and actually go and implement a POC and see what breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The push still seems to be "make OpenStack work on the edge" instead of (what
I think is the quickest / most productive way forward) "write extra tooling
to orchestrate OpenStack on the edge."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some interesting items brought up, like Glance, and image / data
residency. I think that actually engaging with the Glance team might have been
helpful, as they were completely unaware that the discussion was being held,
but the concepts raised sounded interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lasted about an hour or so, before I gave up. From my limited exposure, it
sounded exactly like the discussions I have heard on the Edge Calls, which
were the same as the ones I heard in Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="designate-sessions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Designate Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Designate room was a quiet enough affair, but it marks the first time since
the PTG's started that getting a dedicated room was justified. We did some
onboarding with new folks, and laid out a plan for the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan so far looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A starting point, using signing keys in the Designate database, which we
can use as a jumping point to storing keys in a HSM / Barbican&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People are currently looking at PowerDNS's inline signing as a short term
solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Docs (it will never &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be a priority :) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Shared Zones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Improve the UI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This really relies on us either &lt;code class="bash"&gt;rm -rf openstack/designate-dashboard&lt;/code&gt;
or finding people who understand Angular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tc-qa-tempest-trademark-programs"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TC / QA / Tempest / Trademark Programs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow the mailing list, or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openstack/governance"&gt;openstack/governance&lt;/a&gt; reviews, you may
have seen a long running discussion over where tempest tests used for Trademark
Programs should go. From memory I seem to remember this being raised in Boston,
but it could have been Barcelona. There was tension between QA, me, the InterOp
Work Group, and others about the location. Chris Dent covered this pretty well
in his &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anticdent.org/tag/tc.html"&gt;TC updates&lt;/a&gt; over the last while, so I am not going to rehash it, but
it does look like we finally have some sort of agreement on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/550571/"&gt;location&lt;/a&gt;,
after what was 2 other times I thought we had agreement :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="board-of-directors-meeting"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Board of Directors Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OpenStack Board of Directors met on the first day of the PTG. This was an
issue in its own right, which was highlighted in a thread on the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/foundation/2018-January/002558.html"&gt;foundation list&lt;/a&gt;. Thankfully, I have been told that this situation will not
happen again (I can't seem to find any record of the decision, so it may have
been an informal board discussion, but if anyone from the board is reading,
replying to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/foundation/2018-January/002558.html"&gt;foundation list&lt;/a&gt; would be great.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it met on day one, I didn't get to see much - I arrived to wait for the
Add On Trademark program approvals, and happened to catch a very interesting
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1_N7xhzwk6HzCl0fMm_cWfQ2UFu8bOaZYD2OOAV4y5yQ/edit#slide=id.g33768e8068_2_244"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; by Dims, Chris and Melvin. I then got to see the board approve
DNS as a Trademark add on, which is great for the project, and people who want
a constant DNSaaS experience across multiple clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/foundation/2018-March/002570.html"&gt;Johnathon Price's Board Recap&lt;/a&gt; is also a good overview, with links to things
that were presented at the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-board-community-and-how-we-interact"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Board, Community, and how we interact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One topic that was highlighted by the &lt;a class="reference internal" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/dublin-ptg-summary/#tc-qa-tempest-trademark-programs"&gt;TC / QA / Tempest / Trademark Programs&lt;/a&gt;
discussion was that the QA team is very under resourced. This, combined with
the board discussing &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anticdent.org/tc-report-18-10.html#talking-about-the-ptg-at-the-ptg"&gt;future of the PTGs&lt;/a&gt; due to cost makes me very worried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation has (in my mind) two main focuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote the use of the software or IP produced by people working on projects
under the foundation, and protect its reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empower the developers working on said software or IP to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my eyes, Trademark programs are very much part of #1, and the board should
either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fund / find resources for the QA team, to ensure they have enough bandwidth
to maintain all trademark programs, the associated tests, and tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fund / find a team that does it separately, but removes the entire burden
from the QA team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PTG falls firmly under #2. I was initially a PTG skeptic, but I really
think it works as an event, and adds &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; more value than the old
mid-cycles did. I understand it has problems, but without it, teams will go
back to the mid cycles, which may have looked cheaper at first glance, but
for some people either meant multiple trips, or missing discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One very disappointing thing to see was the list of Travel Support Program
donors - there was some very generous individuals in the community that stood
up and donated, but none of the corporate foundation members contributed. This,
with members being added to the foundation that seem to stop at paying the
membership fee (see &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackalytics.com/?release=all&amp;amp;company=tencent"&gt;tencent&lt;/a&gt; who were added at the Sydney board meeting),
makes me wonder about the value placed on the community by the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the OpenStack Foundation is diversifying its portfolio of projects
beyond just the OpenStack Project (this is going to get confusing :/), but
we should still be supporting the community that currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-great-write-ups"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other great write ups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This turned into a bit of a PTG + 2 weeks after update, so here are some other
write ups I have read over the last week or so, and prompted me to remember
things that I would have otherwise forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anticdent.org/tc-report-18-10.html"&gt;Chris Dent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gazlene.net/dublin-ptg.html"&gt;Colleen Murphy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.adamspiers.org/2018/03/09/openstack-ptg-dublin/"&gt;Adam Spiers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://markvoelker.github.io/blog/dublin-ptg-edge-sessions/"&gt;Mark Voelker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-hotel"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, I saved the best until last. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.doylecollection.com/hotels/the-croke-park-hotel"&gt;Croke Park Hotel&lt;/a&gt; was absolutely
amazing during the conference. When we needed to leave the main venue on
Thursday, they managed the transition of a few hundred developers into all the
public spaces we could find extremely well. They kept us fed, watered and happy
the entire time we were in the hotel. The fact they managed to do this, while
not leaving the hotel to go home and sleep themselves! I cannot say enough good
things about them, and encourage anyone who is looking for a hotel in Dublin to
stay there, or is running an event to use Croke Park and the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Recap links --&gt;
&lt;!-- oslo.limits links --&gt;
&lt;!-- TC / Tempest --&gt;
&lt;!-- BOD --&gt;
&lt;!-- Misc --&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/dublin-ptg-summary/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I have heard of companies running Newton / Ocata Designate (and other projects) on clouds as old as Liberty.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>dublin</category><category>openstack</category><category>snow</category><category>snowpenstack</category><category>summit</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/dublin-ptg-summary/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 19:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sydney OpenStack Summit</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/sydney-openstack-summit/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/9v91EBE02VNZ1fSWcd8JoH7TgPLYhSKXuKrMkqQgSwMHcsw8Im71eM01j6zolH-GuP5XqrAeq4m-GT9Yx4dZXZ_DfND-XWgqvIP64oQwQC-vZgnoLZZ3O-mnOPhQRpouOBscymYBkNelPpg5g2RRy6mXnT9e6lAVy6HGewxRRTL0VOdNApenH_zr-FeRLu_rAOs6WArITF2EbvBsXH74b3EPIGO3BeKlejiC2kSp5Xdj5u7KADXphRazHEVuB8sHegnu0CbZZ2xVLynxvgoSUBPlcwtMUhr87J8_clj0aXIksl-PAWFbhgt7xYlzBkoA1DHsDs5Vw7Cuuah-nycRYRhcSzcFIOvW7L8qWpwHXoD7Xay-DXlqfIYEZjfZc0drpV4AEAnzIaKgIa2PJsFfpiq4hqMv9T59bSIj-EX_wdQ2vXCOzokeZp2t9xCtbIeync9QR_Ij7eXJh_2XHAlLXoR7XrLsY8RiDfrmXSQWVgjEiDGd7urFn6-r3kHLj8QsYRL3ehjfr7GlMtHWuXLkadhblQYpIhnSI-aeEe6NjlXicdMKC43tpWGZkELO9Xm6I82xxycCU68q_g5Sy7BW2_BF7ERp8rNOZg2W4WFJXoySa2fsJitydiJJUvlLSnopYp5GUytsxiMie9fEXQwriFItXlFnXtZsOB8=w1440-h691-no" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/9v91EBE02VNZ1fSWcd8JoH7TgPLYhSKXuKrMkqQgSwMHcsw8Im71eM01j6zolH-GuP5XqrAeq4m-GT9Yx4dZXZ_DfND-XWgqvIP64oQwQC-vZgnoLZZ3O-mnOPhQRpouOBscymYBkNelPpg5g2RRy6mXnT9e6lAVy6HGewxRRTL0VOdNApenH_zr-FeRLu_rAOs6WArITF2EbvBsXH74b3EPIGO3BeKlejiC2kSp5Xdj5u7KADXphRazHEVuB8sHegnu0CbZZ2xVLynxvgoSUBPlcwtMUhr87J8_clj0aXIksl-PAWFbhgt7xYlzBkoA1DHsDs5Vw7Cuuah-nycRYRhcSzcFIOvW7L8qWpwHXoD7Xay-DXlqfIYEZjfZc0drpV4AEAnzIaKgIa2PJsFfpiq4hqMv9T59bSIj-EX_wdQ2vXCOzokeZp2t9xCtbIeync9QR_Ij7eXJh_2XHAlLXoR7XrLsY8RiDfrmXSQWVgjEiDGd7urFn6-r3kHLj8QsYRL3ehjfr7GlMtHWuXLkadhblQYpIhnSI-aeEe6NjlXicdMKC43tpWGZkELO9Xm6I82xxycCU68q_g5Sy7BW2_BF7ERp8rNOZg2W4WFJXoySa2fsJitydiJJUvlLSnopYp5GUytsxiMie9fEXQwriFItXlFnXtZsOB8=w1440-h691-no"&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-down-under"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OpenStack Down Under&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the travelling circus that is the OpenStack summit migrated to
Sydney. A lot of us in Europe / North America found out exactly how far away
from our normal venues it really is. (#openstacksummit on twitter for the days
before the summit was an entertaining read :) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday-board-joint-leadership-meeting"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday Board / Joint Leadership Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was in Sydney, and staying across the road from the meeting, I decided to
drop in and listen. It was an interesting discussion, with a couple of
highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Dent had a very interesting item about developer satisfaction - he has
blogged about it on his blog: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anticdent.org/openstack-developer-satisfaction.html"&gt;anticdent.org&lt;/a&gt; and it is well worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnathon Bryce lead the presentation of a proposed new expansion of the
foundation, which he touched on in the Keynote the next day - I have a few
concerns, but they are all much longer term issues, and may just be my own
interal biases. I think the first new addition to the foundation will let us
know how the rest of the process is going to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleen Murphy and Julia Kreger told us that they (along with Flavio Percoco)
will be starting research to help improve our inclusiveness in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last item was brought forward by 2 board members, and they focused on LTS
(Long Term Support / Stable) branches. The time from an upstream release until
a user has it in production is actually long than expected - with a lot of time
being used by distros packaging and ensuring installers are up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that by the time users have a release in production, the upstream
branches may be fully deprecated. There was a follow up Forum Session, and
there is now an effort to co-ordinate a new methodology for long term
collaboration in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/LTS-proposal"&gt;LTS Etherpad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be an assumption that distros are keeping actual git branches
around for the longer term, and not layering patches inside of deb / rpm files,
which I think is much more likely. I hope this effort succeeds, but my cynical
side thinks this is more of a "fix it for us" cry, than "help us fix it". I
suppose we will see if people show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slide from this section was not discussed but concerned me. It was talking
about having an enforced "TC Roadmap" which had lines from various workgroups
and SIGs. Coming from a project that gets a lot of "Can you do &lt;cite&gt;x&lt;/cite&gt; feature?"
(to which I usually respond with "Do you have anyone to write the code?") this
concerns me. I understand that it can be hard to get things changed in
OpenStack, really I do, but a top down enforced "Roadmap" is not the way
forward.
Honestly, that two board members of an Open Source foundation think it
is is worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="designate"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Designate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designate had 3 sessions in Sydney:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our project update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project On Boarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ops Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project update was good - much improved from Boston, where the 2 presenters
were not paid to work on the project. We covered the major potential features,
where we were for Cycle goals (both Queens goals completed, and Pike goals
underway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project on boarding was not hugely attended, but I am hoping that was a side
effect of the summit being both smaller and far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/small_far_away.gif" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/small_far_away.gif"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ops feedback was great - we got a lot of bugs that were impacting our users and
deployers, and collected it in our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/SYD-forum-designate-feedback"&gt;Feedback Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; (any comments welcome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cross-project-work"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cross Project Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to quite a few cross project sessions - there was a good amount of
discussion, and some useful work came out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="application-tokens"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Application Tokens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that had completely slipped past me until now, but the ideas
were great, and it would have made things I have done in previous companies
much much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="healthchecks-per-service"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Healthchecks per service&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came to a good agreement on how we can do standardised health checks across
OpenStack, we now need to write a spec and start coding a new piece of
middleware :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="edge-computing"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Edge Computing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so sure this was worth a vist - it was much more crowded than any of the
other Forum sessions I went to, and ended up Bike Shedding on where the Edge
ends (we literally spent 10 mins talking about if a car was part of the Edge
or a thing managed by the edge.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept hearing "smaller and lighter OpenStack" in that session, but have yet
to hear what is too heavy about what we currently have. Nearly all our service
scale down to some extent, and you can run a complete infrastructure on an 8GB
VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a good summit - not too busy, and short. Looking forward to not
traveling for the next PTG, I think the DUB -&amp;gt; DOH -&amp;gt; SYD and back drained the
enthusiasm for flights for the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>tokyo</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/sydney-openstack-summit/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:35:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack TC Nomination</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/me.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would like to submit my candidacy for the Technical Committee for the
upcoming election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/em&gt; So, I bit the bullet and ran for the TC :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been contributing to OpenStack since the Havana cycle &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id5" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; mainly in
Designate. I have also sporadically gotten involved with the TC, and its
meetings since Designate applied for incubation all the way back in Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been PTL for Designate for Mitaka, Newton, Ocata and the Queens cycle,
and a core for a longer period. I was also PTL for the Global Load Balancing
before it was an unfortunate early casualty of the recent reshuffling within
sponsoring organizations in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of previous projects, I was both a developer and a heavy user of
OpenStack. As part of contributing to the Kubernetes OpenStack integration
we ran into a lot of the problems that impact our users, and people who
try to integrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that we all ready have a great base structure in place to help
OpenStack evolve, and part of that is too have a group of people from different
companies, backgrounds, genders and cultures to drive the project in the
Technical Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe my experience working in a younger, smaller project within
OpenStack is a benefit, along with the experience of working on software as an
end user of OpenStack I can help us ensure the Technical Committee is mindful
of the unique challenges these projects and users can face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not traditionally been shy about broaching these topics in the past &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id6" id="id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id7" id="id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id8" id="id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;, but I feel it is time I started follow through, and help guide the
resolution for these questions, and I now have an employeer who is supportive
of me spending more time in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do really like this community, and I want us to grow, expand and evolve the
software we write, without changing what we stand for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to read this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graham Hayes (mugsie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id5" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stackalytics.com/?release=all&amp;amp;metric=commits&amp;amp;user_id=grahamhayes"&gt;http://stackalytics.com/?release=all&amp;amp;metric=commits&amp;amp;user_id=grahamhayes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id6" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id7" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/"&gt;http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id8" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/#id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/312267/"&gt;https://review.openstack.org/#/c/312267/&lt;/a&gt; (and related discussion)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>elections</category><category>openstack</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-tc-nomination/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 13:02:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack Designate - Where we are.</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/me.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been asked a few times recently "What is the state of the Designate
project?", "How is Designate getting on?", and by people who know what is
happening "What are you going to do about Designate?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, all of this is depressing to me, and the people that I have
worked with for the last number of years to make Designate a truly useful,
feature rich project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/em&gt; for this - Designate is not in a sustainable place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start out - Designate has always been a small project. DNS does not have
massive &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; appeal - its not shiny, pretty, or something you see on the
front page of HackerNews (unless it breaks - then oh boy do people become DNS
experts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line a previous PTL for the project used to use, and I have happily robbed is
"DNS is like plumbing, no one cares about it until it breaks, and then you are
standing knee deep in $expletive". (As an aside, that was the reason we chose
the crocodile as our mascot - its basically a dinosaur, old as dirt, and when
it bites it causes some serious complications).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately that comes over into the development of DNS products sometimes.
DNSaaS is a check box on a tender response, an assumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky in the beginning - we had 2 large(ish) public clouds that needed
DNS services, and nothing currently existed in the eco-system, so we got
funding for a team from a few sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a ton done in that period - we moved from a v1 API which was
synchronous to a new v2 async API, we massively increased the amount of DNS
servers we supported, and added new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this didn't last. Internal priorities within companies
sponsoring the development changed, and we started to shed contributors, which
happens, however disappointing. Usually when this happens if a project is
important enough the community will pick up where the previous group left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have yet to see many (meaningful) commits from the community though. We
have some great deployers who will file bugs, and if they can put up patch
sets - but they are (incredibly valuable and appreciated) tactical
contributions. A project cannot survive on them, and we are no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does that leave us? Let have a look at how many actual commits we
have had:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Commits per cycle&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="61%"&gt;
&lt;col width="39%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Havana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;172&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Icehouse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;165&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Juno&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;254&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kilo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;340&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Liberty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;327&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mitaka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;246&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Newton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;299&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ocata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next cycle, we are going to have 2 community goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control Plane API endpoints deployment via WSGI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 3.5 functional testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would have been actually OK for the tempest one - we were one of the first
external repo based plug-ins with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openstack/designate-tempest-plugin"&gt;designate-tempest-plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For WSGI based APIs, this will be a chunk of work - due to our internal code
structure splitting out the API is going to be ... an issue. (and I think it
will be harder than most people expect - anyone using olso.service has
eventlet imported - I am not sure how that affects running in a WSGI server)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.5 - I have no idea. We can't even run all our unit tests on python
3.5, so I suspect getting functional testing may be an issue. And, convincing
management that re-factoring parts of the code base due to "community goals"
or a future potential pay-off can be more difficult than it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/oct-2016-projects-prod.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/oct-2016-projects-prod.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have a situation where the largest "non-core" project &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id6" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; in the tent
has a tiny number of developers working on it. 42% of deployers are evaluating
Designate, so we should see this start to increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-did-this-happen"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How did this happen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most situations, there is no single cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly there may have been fault on the side of the Designate leadership.
We had started out as a small team, and had built a huge amount of trust and
respect based on in person interactions over a few years, which meant that
there was a fair bit of "tribal knowledge" in the heads of a few people, and
that new people had a hard time becoming part of the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, due to volume of work done by this small group, a lot of users / distros
were OK leaving us work - some of us were also running a production designate
service during this time, so we knew what we needed to develop, and we had
pretty quick feedback when we made a mistake, or caused a bug. All of this
resulted in the major development cost being funded by two companies, which
left us vulnerable to changes in direction from those companies. Then that
shoe dropped. We are now one corporate change of direction from having no
cores on the project being paid to work on the project. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id7" id="id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preceding this, the governance of OpenStack changed to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/tc/resolutions/20141202-project-structure-reform-spec.html"&gt;Big Tent&lt;/a&gt;
While this change was a good thing for the OpenStack project as a
whole it had quite a bad impact on us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre Big Tent, you got integrated. This was at least a cycle, where you moved
docs to docs.openstack.org, integrated with QA testing tooling, got packaged
by Linux distros, and build cross project features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this was a selective thing, there was teams available to help with that,
docs teams would help with content (and tooling - docs was a mass of XML back
then), QA would help with tempest and devstack, horizon would help with panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Big Tent, there just wasn't resources to do this - the scope of the project
expansion was huge. However the big tent happened (in my opinion - I have
written about this before) before the horizontal / cross project teams were
ready. They stuck to covering the "integrated" projects, which was all
they could do at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This left us in a position of having to reimplement tooling, figure out
what tooling we did have access to, and migrate everything we had on our
own. And, as a project that (at our peak level of contribution) only ever had
5% of the number of contributors compared to a project like nova,  this put
quite a load on our developers. Things like grenade, tempest and horizon
plug-ins, took weeks to figure out all of which took time from other vital
things like docs, functional tests and getting designate into other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the companies who invested in designate had a QE engineer that used to
contribute, and I can honestly say that the quality of our testing improved 10
fold during the time he worked with us. Not just from in repo tests, but from
standing up full deployment stacks, and trying to break them - we learned a lot
about how we could improve things from his expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is kind of the point I think. Nobody is amazing at everything. You need
people with domain knowledge to work on these areas. If you asked me to do a
multi-node grenade job, I would either start drinking, throw my laptop at you
or do both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have some of these problems to this day - most of our docs are
in a messy pile in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/designate"&gt;docs.openstack.org/developer/designate&lt;/a&gt;
while we still have a small amount of old functional tests that are not ported
from our old non plug-in style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this adds up to make projects like Designate much less attractive
to users - we just need to look at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/software/releases/newton/components/designate"&gt;project navigator&lt;/a&gt; to see what a bad
image potential users get of us. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id8" id="id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; This is for a project that was ran as a
full (non beta) service in a public cloud. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id9" id="id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-too-now-then"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where too now then?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is where I call out to people who actually use the project - don't
jump ship and use something else because of the picture I have painted. We are
a dedicated team, who cares about the project. We just need some help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there are large telcos who use Designate. I am sure there is tooling,
or docs build up in these companies that could be very useful to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every commercial OpenStack distro has Designate. Some have had it since
the beginning. Again, developers, docs, tooling, testers, anything and
everything is welcome. We don't need a massive amount of resources - we are a
small ish, stable, project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need developers with upstream time allocated, and the budget to go to events
like the PTG - for cross project work, and internal designate road map, these
events form the core of how we work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also need help from cross project teams - the work done by them is brilliant
but it can be hard for smaller projects to consume. We have had a lot of
progress since the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/"&gt;Leveller Playing Field&lt;/a&gt; debate, but a lot of work is
still optimised for the larger teams who get direct support, or well resourced
teams who can dedicate people to the implementation of plugins / code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone I was talking to recently said - AWS is not winning public cloud
because of commodity compute (that does help - a lot), but because of the
added services that make using the cloud, well, cloud like. OpenStack needs to
decide that either it is just compute, or if it wants the eco-system. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id10" id="id5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;
Designate is far from alone in this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to talk to anyone about helping to fill in the needed resources -
Designate is a project that started in the very office I am writing this blog
post in, and something I want to last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a visual this is Designate team in Atlanta, just before we got incubated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/ATL.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/ATL.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this was our last mid cycle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/mid-cycle.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/mid-cycle.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and in Atlanta at the PTG, there will be two of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id6" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/analytics"&gt;Oct-2016&lt;/a&gt; User Survey Designate was deployed in 23% of clouds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id7" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I have been lucky to have a management chain that is OK with me
spending some time on Designate, and have not asked me to take time off
for Summits or Gatherings, but my day job is working on a completely
different project.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id8" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I do have other issues with the metrics - mainly that we existed before
leaving stackforge, and some of the other stats are set so
high, that non "core" projects will probably never meet them.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id9" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I recently went to an internal training talk, where they were talking
about new features in Newton. There was a whole slide about how projects
had improved, or gotten worse on these scores. A whole slide. With
tables of scores, and I think there may have even been a graph.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id10" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Now, I am slightly biased, but I would argue that DNS is needed in
commodity compute, but again, that is my view.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>designate</category><category>openstack</category><category>project update</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Non Candidacy for Designate PTL</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-2McNPwq/0/S/IMG_3854-S.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-2McNPwq/0/X3/IMG_3854-X3.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-2McNPwq/0/X3/IMG_3854-X3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl-pike"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Non Candidacy for Designate PTL - Pike&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may have guessed from the title, I have decided that the time has come to step aside as PTL
for the upcoming cycle. It is unfortunate, but my work has pivoted in a different direction over the last
year (containers all the way down man - but hey, I got part of my wish to write Golang, just not on the
project I envisaged :) ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, I have been trying to PTL out of hours for the last cycle and a half. Unfortunatly, this has had a
bad impact on this cycle, and I don't think we should repeat the pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have done some great work over the last year or so - Worker Model, the &lt;code class="python"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Zone&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; work,
the new dashboard, being one of the first projects to have an external tempest plugin and getting lost in
the west of Ireland in the aftermath of the flooding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-h4gGtxX/0/X3/IMG_3869-X3.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-h4gGtxX/0/X3/IMG_3869-X3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can honestly say, I have enjoyed my entire time with this team, from our first meeting in Austin, back in
the beginning of 2014, the whole way through to today. We have always been a small team, but when I think back
to what we have produced over the last few years, I am incredibly proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is healthy, and I have been in a leadership position in Designate longer than most, and no project should
rely on a person or persons to continue to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will stick around on IRC, and still remain a member of the core review team, as a lot of the roadmap is still in
the heads of myself and 2 or 3 others, but my main aim will be to document the roadmap in a single place, and not
just in thousands of etherpads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a fun journey - I have gotten to work with some great people, see some amazing places, work on really
interestig problems and contribute to a project that was close to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an easy thing to do, but I think the time is right for the project and me to let someone else make
their stamp on the project, and bring it to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominations close soon &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id4" id="id1"&gt;[0]&lt;/a&gt; so please start thinking about if you would like to run or not. If anyone has any questions
about the role, please drop me an email &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id5" id="id2"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; or ping me &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id6" id="id3"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="irc://chat.freenode.net/#openstack-dns"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for this opportunity to serve the community for so long, it is not something I will forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id4" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id1"&gt;[0]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/election/"&gt;Election Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id5" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id2"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;graham.hayes (a) hpe.com&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id6" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/#id3"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;mugsie&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>designate</category><category>openstack</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/non-candidacy-for-designate-ptl/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 22:16:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Equal Opportunities for all OpenStack Projects</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, two weeks ago, I dropped a TC &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt; and a mailing list &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and
waited for the other foot to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised - no one started shouting at me - but by trying
to not point fingers at individual teams I made the text too convoluted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in an effort to clarify things, here is an overview of what has been said
so far, both in the mailing list and the gerrit review itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="feedback"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
... does this also include plugins within projects, like storage
backends in cinder and hypervisor drivers in nova?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - this was not clear enough. This change is aimed at projects that are
points of significant cross project interaction. While, in the future there may
come a point where Nova Compute Drivers are developed out of tree (though
I doubt it), that is not happening today. As a result, there is no projects in
the list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/reference/projects/index.html"&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; that would need to integrate with Nova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Could you please clarify: do you advocate for a generic plugin interface for
every project, or that each project should expose a plugin interface that
allows plugin to behave as in-tree components? Because the latter is what
happens with Tempest, and I see the former a bit complicated.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every project that has cross project interaction - tempest is a good
example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these projects, they should allow all projects in tree (like Nova,
Neutron, Cinder etc are today), or they should have a plugin interface
(like they currently do), but all projects &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use it, and not use
parts of tempest that are not exposed in that interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would mean that tempest would move the nova, neutron, etc tests to
use the plugin interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that plugin could be kept in the tempest repo, and still maintained
by the QA team, but should use the same interface as the other plugins
that are not in that repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is not just tempest - an incomplete list looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tempest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grende&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horizon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack SDK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searchlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistral&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celiometer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am sure I have missed some obvious ones. (if you see a project missing
let me know on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
I think I disagree here. The root cause is being addressed: external tests can
use the Tempest plugin interface, and use the API, which is being stabilized.
The fact that the Tempest API is partially unstable is a temporary things, due
to the origin of the project and the way the scope was redefined, but again
it's temporary.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the core of a lot of the disagreement - this is only temporary,
it will all be fixed in the future, and it should stay this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the discrepancy between projects is not temporary. The specific
problems I have highlighted in the thread for one of the projects is temporary,
but I beleive the only long-term solution is to remove the difference between
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Before we start making lots of specific rules about how teams
coordinate, I would like to understand the problem those rules are meant
to solve, so thank you for providing that example.
...
It's not clear yet whether there needs to be a new policy to change the
existing intent, or if a discussion just hasn't happened, or if someone
simply needs to edit some code.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is a big push back on editing code to help plugins from
some of the projects. Again, having the differing access between projects will
continue to exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Change the name of the resolution"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—(Paraphrase from a few people)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was done in the last patchset. I think the Level Playing Field title
bounced around my head from the other resolution that was titled Level Playing
Field. It may have been confusing alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-areas"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Areas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I have been picking on tempest a little too much, it just captures
the current issues perfectly, and a large number of the community have some
knowledge of it, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is other areas across OpenStack the need attention as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="horizon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Horizon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizon privileged projects have access to much more panels than
plugins (service status, quotas, overviews etc).
Plugins have to rely on tarballs of horizon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-client"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack CLI privileged projects have access to more commands, as
plugins cannot hook in to them (e.g. quotas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grenade"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grenade&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins may or may not have tempest tests ran (I think that patch
merged), they have to use parts of tempest I was told explicitly
plugins should not use to get the tests to run at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now add install guides and hook into the API Reference, and API
guides. This is great - and I am really happy about it. We still have
issues trying to integrate with other areas in docs, and most non docs
privileged projects end up with massive amounts of users docs in
docs.openstack.org/developer/&amp;lt;project&amp;gt; , which is not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 21:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack - A leveler playing field</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just proposed a review to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/342366"&gt;openstack/governance&lt;/a&gt;  repo [0] that aims
to have everything across OpenStack be plugin based for all cross
project interaction, or allow all projects access to the same internal
APIs and I wanted to give a bit of background on my motivation, and how
it came about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a smaller project, I can see issues for new projects,
smaller projects, and projects that may not be seen as "important".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a smaller project trying to fit into cross project initiatives,
(and yes, make sure our software looks at least OK in the
Project Navigator) the process can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of projects / repositories have plugin interfaces, but also
have project integrations in tree, that do not follow the plugin
interface. This makes it difficult to see what a plugin can, and
should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we moved to the big tent, we wanted as a community to move to
a flatter model, removing the old integrated status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we still have areas when some projects are more equal -
there is a lingering set of projects who were integrated at the point
in time that we moved, and have preferential status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the effects are hard to see, and are not insurmountable, but
do cause projects to re-invent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, quotas - there is no way for a project that is not nova,
neutron, cinder to hook into the standard CLI, or UI for setting
quotas. They can be done as either extra commands
(openstack dns quota set --foo bar) or as custom panels, but not
the way other quotas get set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempest plugins are another example. Approximately 30 of the 36
current plugins are using resources that are not supposed to be
used, and are an unstable interface. Projects in tree in tempest
are at a much better position, as any change to the internal
API will have to be fixed before the gate merges, but other
out of tree plugins are in a place where they can be broken at any
point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is meant to single out projects, or teams. A lot
of the projects that are in this situation have inordinate amounts of
work placed on them by the big-tent, and I can emphasize with why things
are this way. These were the examples that currently stick out
in my mind, and I think we have come to a point where we need to make
a change as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By moving to a "plugins for all" model, these issues are reduced.
It undoubtedly will cause more, but it is closer to our goal
of Recognizing all our community is part of OpenStack, and
differentiate projects by tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This won't be a change that happens tomorrow, next week, or even next
cycle, but think as a goal, we should start moving in this direction
as soon as we can, and start building momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;This was originally posted to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;openstack-dev&lt;/a&gt; mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:30:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designate Newton Design Summit</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-newton-design-summit/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a5/Austin_Evening.jpg/1024px-Austin_Evening.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-wSSCDSC/0/X3/IMG_20160427_201746-X3.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-wSSCDSC/0/X3/IMG_20160427_201746-X3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this on a plane on the way home from Austin, TX where we just
finished up the Newton design summit for OpenStack, and finished it a few days
later - please excuse any wierdness in syntax or flow :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austin was its usual weird, wacky, wonderful self. Everytime we are here, I
have a great time, I just can't deal with the heat :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summit format this year worked really well - I pretty much stayed in the
design summit hotel for the week - and got some very good work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="months-on-where-are-we"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6 Months On: Where are we&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I did before this design summit was to look at what we had
achived last cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a quiet cycle overall, but we did merge some vital features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operators no longer need to use the awfull config format we created for pools
in Kilo, we now have a much easier to read YAML file that is loaded into the
database via the &lt;code class="bash"&gt;designate-manage&lt;/code&gt; cli, we now actually support multiple
pools in a real way with the addition of a schedular in
&lt;code class="bash"&gt;designate-central&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-are-we-going"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where are we going?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So - the point of the design summit is to plan the future of the projects - and
designate is no execption. We were in a (very nice boardroom) room for a few
hours - and we talked through quite a few things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-p8SxMgH/0/X2/IMG_20160427_140741-X2.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-p8SxMgH/0/X2/IMG_20160427_140741-X2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/newton-design-designate"&gt;etherpads&lt;/a&gt; for the summit are available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="golang-replacement-of-minidns"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Golang Replacement of MiniDNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nicer things about our current architecture is the flexibility that
we have because we use the standard DNS protocols to update the target DNS
servers. This has the downside however, that we are writing code that deals with
DNS packets in python, which is slow. timsim from RackSpace has writen a POC
in go that has a very large perfomance improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This needs to documented, and permission requested from the TC to move this
component to Go, (and will be a separate post in its own right).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we got back it turned out that we were not the only project considering
this, and swift actually have a feature branch with code in place. So, based on
this, we are going to collaborate with them on the integration of Go to
OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="worker-model"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Worker Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we dicussed in Galway - we need to replace the current &lt;code class="bash"&gt;*-manager&lt;/code&gt; services
with a generic service that can scale out horizontally. As part of this we
planned out our upgrade and implementation plans for these services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="docs-deprications-and-more-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docs, Deprications and more Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docs were a common theme - we were asked to improve them, and also have them
located in the main docs on the OpenStack.org website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a member of the docs team in the room, who gave us some great guidenance
on how to include our docs in the correct place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vmt-the-application-process"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VMT - The application process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On of the teams that supports OpenStack is the Vunrebility Management Team.
They deal with disclosures and assigning OSSA numbers to issues that could present
and issue to our deployers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a session this summit on how that process might work, and designate
was one of the projects chosen to be used as a pilot as I have previously
produced Threat Analysis documentation for Designate inside of Hewlett Packard
Enterprise - this information is currently being processed for release to
the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="searchlight"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Searchlight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searchlight is a new (ish) project in OpenStack that enables true searching
capabilities on clouds. We have a designate plugin, but there are issues
with how we emit notifications from the v1 and the v2 API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided that when we move the Horizon panels to v2, we will just listen for
v2 notifications in Searchlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="api-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;API Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an interesting session on how the community are moving to document
their APIs. It will now reside in the projects repo, and is based on a
custom sphinx extention that was written for OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this progresses we will migrate designate to these docs, and remove our
current docs, as they are much harder to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>austin</category><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-newton-design-summit/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>