<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (openstack)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/openstack.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 23:04:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>OpenStack Summit - Designate Report</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where to start?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tokyo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a place. I thought I was ready for the experience, but this city has
to be visited to understand. From the 2 or 3 different metro systems that snake
across the city, to the 9 story electronics stores, it is something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in a city that has 3 metro lines that don't actually connect it was a nice
change to be able to get reliable public transport :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="design-summit"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design Summit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a much more relaxed summit for Designate. We had done a huge amount of
work in Vancouver, and we were nailing down details and doing cross project work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a few major features discussed, and laid out our priorities for the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nova / Neutron Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pool Scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pool Configuration migration to database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IXFR (Incremental Zone Transfer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ALIAS Record type (Allows for CNAME like records at the root of a DNS Zone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNSSEC (this may drag on for a cycle or two)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nova-neutron-integration"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nova &amp;amp; Neutron Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is progressing pretty well, and Miguel Lavalle has patches up for this. He,
Kiall Mac Innes and Carl Baldwin demoed this in a session on the Thursday. If
you are interested in the idea, it is definitely worth a watch &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AZbiARM9FPM"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pool-scheduler"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pool Scheduler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A vital piece of the pools re architecture that needs to be finished out.
There is no great debate on what we need, and I have taken on the task of
finishing this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pool-configuration-migration-to-database"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pool Configuration migration to database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are current configuration file format is quite complex, and moving it to an API
allows us to iterate on it much quicker, while reducing the complexity of the
config file. I recently had to write an ansible play to write out this file, and
it was not fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiall had a patch up, so we should be able to continue based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ixfr"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IXFR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was quite a lot of discussion on how this will be implemented, both in the
work session, and the 1/2 day session on the Friday. Tim Simmons has stepped up,
to continue the work on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="alias"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ALIAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite a sort after feature - but is quite complex to implement.
The DNS RFCs explicitly ban this behavior, so we have to work the solution
around them. Eric Larson has been doing quite a lot of work on this in Liberty,
and is going to continue in Mitaka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dnssec"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a feature that we have been looking at for a while, but we started to plan
out our roadmap for it recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (I) am allergic to storing private encryption keys in Designate, so we had a
good conversation with Barbican about implementing a signing endpoint that we would
post a hash to. This work is on me to now drive for Mitaka, so we can consume it in N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some raw notes in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/mitaka-designate-summit-roadmap"&gt;etherpad&lt;/a&gt; and I expect we will soon be seeing
specs building out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>tokyo</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 21:18:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>