<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (plugins)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/plugins.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 21:27:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Equal Opportunities for all OpenStack Projects</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, two weeks ago, I dropped a TC &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt; and a mailing list &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and
waited for the other foot to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised - no one started shouting at me - but by trying
to not point fingers at individual teams I made the text too convoluted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in an effort to clarify things, here is an overview of what has been said
so far, both in the mailing list and the gerrit review itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="feedback"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
... does this also include plugins within projects, like storage
backends in cinder and hypervisor drivers in nova?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - this was not clear enough. This change is aimed at projects that are
points of significant cross project interaction. While, in the future there may
come a point where Nova Compute Drivers are developed out of tree (though
I doubt it), that is not happening today. As a result, there is no projects in
the list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/reference/projects/index.html"&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; that would need to integrate with Nova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Could you please clarify: do you advocate for a generic plugin interface for
every project, or that each project should expose a plugin interface that
allows plugin to behave as in-tree components? Because the latter is what
happens with Tempest, and I see the former a bit complicated.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every project that has cross project interaction - tempest is a good
example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these projects, they should allow all projects in tree (like Nova,
Neutron, Cinder etc are today), or they should have a plugin interface
(like they currently do), but all projects &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use it, and not use
parts of tempest that are not exposed in that interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would mean that tempest would move the nova, neutron, etc tests to
use the plugin interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that plugin could be kept in the tempest repo, and still maintained
by the QA team, but should use the same interface as the other plugins
that are not in that repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is not just tempest - an incomplete list looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tempest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grende&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horizon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack SDK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searchlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistral&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celiometer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am sure I have missed some obvious ones. (if you see a project missing
let me know on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
I think I disagree here. The root cause is being addressed: external tests can
use the Tempest plugin interface, and use the API, which is being stabilized.
The fact that the Tempest API is partially unstable is a temporary things, due
to the origin of the project and the way the scope was redefined, but again
it's temporary.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the core of a lot of the disagreement - this is only temporary,
it will all be fixed in the future, and it should stay this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the discrepancy between projects is not temporary. The specific
problems I have highlighted in the thread for one of the projects is temporary,
but I beleive the only long-term solution is to remove the difference between
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Before we start making lots of specific rules about how teams
coordinate, I would like to understand the problem those rules are meant
to solve, so thank you for providing that example.
...
It's not clear yet whether there needs to be a new policy to change the
existing intent, or if a discussion just hasn't happened, or if someone
simply needs to edit some code.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is a big push back on editing code to help plugins from
some of the projects. Again, having the differing access between projects will
continue to exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Change the name of the resolution"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—(Paraphrase from a few people)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was done in the last patchset. I think the Level Playing Field title
bounced around my head from the other resolution that was titled Level Playing
Field. It may have been confusing alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-areas"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Areas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I have been picking on tempest a little too much, it just captures
the current issues perfectly, and a large number of the community have some
knowledge of it, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is other areas across OpenStack the need attention as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="horizon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Horizon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizon privileged projects have access to much more panels than
plugins (service status, quotas, overviews etc).
Plugins have to rely on tarballs of horizon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-client"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack CLI privileged projects have access to more commands, as
plugins cannot hook in to them (e.g. quotas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grenade"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grenade&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins may or may not have tempest tests ran (I think that patch
merged), they have to use parts of tempest I was told explicitly
plugins should not use to get the tests to run at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now add install guides and hook into the API Reference, and API
guides. This is great - and I am really happy about it. We still have
issues trying to integrate with other areas in docs, and most non docs
privileged projects end up with massive amounts of users docs in
docs.openstack.org/developer/&amp;lt;project&amp;gt; , which is not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 21:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack - A leveler playing field</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just proposed a review to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/342366"&gt;openstack/governance&lt;/a&gt;  repo [0] that aims
to have everything across OpenStack be plugin based for all cross
project interaction, or allow all projects access to the same internal
APIs and I wanted to give a bit of background on my motivation, and how
it came about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a smaller project, I can see issues for new projects,
smaller projects, and projects that may not be seen as "important".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a smaller project trying to fit into cross project initiatives,
(and yes, make sure our software looks at least OK in the
Project Navigator) the process can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of projects / repositories have plugin interfaces, but also
have project integrations in tree, that do not follow the plugin
interface. This makes it difficult to see what a plugin can, and
should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we moved to the big tent, we wanted as a community to move to
a flatter model, removing the old integrated status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we still have areas when some projects are more equal -
there is a lingering set of projects who were integrated at the point
in time that we moved, and have preferential status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the effects are hard to see, and are not insurmountable, but
do cause projects to re-invent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, quotas - there is no way for a project that is not nova,
neutron, cinder to hook into the standard CLI, or UI for setting
quotas. They can be done as either extra commands
(openstack dns quota set --foo bar) or as custom panels, but not
the way other quotas get set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempest plugins are another example. Approximately 30 of the 36
current plugins are using resources that are not supposed to be
used, and are an unstable interface. Projects in tree in tempest
are at a much better position, as any change to the internal
API will have to be fixed before the gate merges, but other
out of tree plugins are in a place where they can be broken at any
point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is meant to single out projects, or teams. A lot
of the projects that are in this situation have inordinate amounts of
work placed on them by the big-tent, and I can emphasize with why things
are this way. These were the examples that currently stick out
in my mind, and I think we have come to a point where we need to make
a change as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By moving to a "plugins for all" model, these issues are reduced.
It undoubtedly will cause more, but it is closer to our goal
of Recognizing all our community is part of OpenStack, and
differentiate projects by tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This won't be a change that happens tomorrow, next week, or even next
cycle, but think as a goal, we should start moving in this direction
as soon as we can, and start building momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;This was originally posted to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;openstack-dev&lt;/a&gt; mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:30:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>