<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (tc)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/tc.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 17:52:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>OpenStack Designate - Where we are.</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/me.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been asked a few times recently "What is the state of the Designate
project?", "How is Designate getting on?", and by people who know what is
happening "What are you going to do about Designate?".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, all of this is depressing to me, and the people that I have
worked with for the last number of years to make Designate a truly useful,
feature rich project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/em&gt; for this - Designate is not in a sustainable place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start out - Designate has always been a small project. DNS does not have
massive &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; appeal - its not shiny, pretty, or something you see on the
front page of HackerNews (unless it breaks - then oh boy do people become DNS
experts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A line a previous PTL for the project used to use, and I have happily robbed is
"DNS is like plumbing, no one cares about it until it breaks, and then you are
standing knee deep in $expletive". (As an aside, that was the reason we chose
the crocodile as our mascot - its basically a dinosaur, old as dirt, and when
it bites it causes some serious complications).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately that comes over into the development of DNS products sometimes.
DNSaaS is a check box on a tender response, an assumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky in the beginning - we had 2 large(ish) public clouds that needed
DNS services, and nothing currently existed in the eco-system, so we got
funding for a team from a few sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a ton done in that period - we moved from a v1 API which was
synchronous to a new v2 async API, we massively increased the amount of DNS
servers we supported, and added new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this didn't last. Internal priorities within companies
sponsoring the development changed, and we started to shed contributors, which
happens, however disappointing. Usually when this happens if a project is
important enough the community will pick up where the previous group left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have yet to see many (meaningful) commits from the community though. We
have some great deployers who will file bugs, and if they can put up patch
sets - but they are (incredibly valuable and appreciated) tactical
contributions. A project cannot survive on them, and we are no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does that leave us? Let have a look at how many actual commits we
have had:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;caption&gt;Commits per cycle&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="61%"&gt;
&lt;col width="39%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Havana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;172&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Icehouse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;165&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Juno&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;254&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Kilo&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;340&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Liberty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;327&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mitaka&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;246&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Newton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;299&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ocata&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;98&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next cycle, we are going to have 2 community goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control Plane API endpoints deployment via WSGI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python 3.5 functional testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would have been actually OK for the tempest one - we were one of the first
external repo based plug-ins with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openstack/designate-tempest-plugin"&gt;designate-tempest-plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For WSGI based APIs, this will be a chunk of work - due to our internal code
structure splitting out the API is going to be ... an issue. (and I think it
will be harder than most people expect - anyone using olso.service has
eventlet imported - I am not sure how that affects running in a WSGI server)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.5 - I have no idea. We can't even run all our unit tests on python
3.5, so I suspect getting functional testing may be an issue. And, convincing
management that re-factoring parts of the code base due to "community goals"
or a future potential pay-off can be more difficult than it should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/oct-2016-projects-prod.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/oct-2016-projects-prod.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have a situation where the largest "non-core" project &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id6" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; in the tent
has a tiny number of developers working on it. 42% of deployers are evaluating
Designate, so we should see this start to increase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-did-this-happen"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How did this happen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most situations, there is no single cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly there may have been fault on the side of the Designate leadership.
We had started out as a small team, and had built a huge amount of trust and
respect based on in person interactions over a few years, which meant that
there was a fair bit of "tribal knowledge" in the heads of a few people, and
that new people had a hard time becoming part of the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, due to volume of work done by this small group, a lot of users / distros
were OK leaving us work - some of us were also running a production designate
service during this time, so we knew what we needed to develop, and we had
pretty quick feedback when we made a mistake, or caused a bug. All of this
resulted in the major development cost being funded by two companies, which
left us vulnerable to changes in direction from those companies. Then that
shoe dropped. We are now one corporate change of direction from having no
cores on the project being paid to work on the project. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id7" id="id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preceding this, the governance of OpenStack changed to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/tc/resolutions/20141202-project-structure-reform-spec.html"&gt;Big Tent&lt;/a&gt;
While this change was a good thing for the OpenStack project as a
whole it had quite a bad impact on us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre Big Tent, you got integrated. This was at least a cycle, where you moved
docs to docs.openstack.org, integrated with QA testing tooling, got packaged
by Linux distros, and build cross project features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this was a selective thing, there was teams available to help with that,
docs teams would help with content (and tooling - docs was a mass of XML back
then), QA would help with tempest and devstack, horizon would help with panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Big Tent, there just wasn't resources to do this - the scope of the project
expansion was huge. However the big tent happened (in my opinion - I have
written about this before) before the horizontal / cross project teams were
ready. They stuck to covering the "integrated" projects, which was all
they could do at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This left us in a position of having to reimplement tooling, figure out
what tooling we did have access to, and migrate everything we had on our
own. And, as a project that (at our peak level of contribution) only ever had
5% of the number of contributors compared to a project like nova,  this put
quite a load on our developers. Things like grenade, tempest and horizon
plug-ins, took weeks to figure out all of which took time from other vital
things like docs, functional tests and getting designate into other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the companies who invested in designate had a QE engineer that used to
contribute, and I can honestly say that the quality of our testing improved 10
fold during the time he worked with us. Not just from in repo tests, but from
standing up full deployment stacks, and trying to break them - we learned a lot
about how we could improve things from his expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is kind of the point I think. Nobody is amazing at everything. You need
people with domain knowledge to work on these areas. If you asked me to do a
multi-node grenade job, I would either start drinking, throw my laptop at you
or do both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still have some of these problems to this day - most of our docs are
in a messy pile in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/designate"&gt;docs.openstack.org/developer/designate&lt;/a&gt;
while we still have a small amount of old functional tests that are not ported
from our old non plug-in style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this adds up to make projects like Designate much less attractive
to users - we just need to look at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/software/releases/newton/components/designate"&gt;project navigator&lt;/a&gt; to see what a bad
image potential users get of us. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id8" id="id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; This is for a project that was ran as a
full (non beta) service in a public cloud. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id9" id="id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-too-now-then"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where too now then?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is where I call out to people who actually use the project - don't
jump ship and use something else because of the picture I have painted. We are
a dedicated team, who cares about the project. We just need some help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there are large telcos who use Designate. I am sure there is tooling,
or docs build up in these companies that could be very useful to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every commercial OpenStack distro has Designate. Some have had it since
the beginning. Again, developers, docs, tooling, testers, anything and
everything is welcome. We don't need a massive amount of resources - we are a
small ish, stable, project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need developers with upstream time allocated, and the budget to go to events
like the PTG - for cross project work, and internal designate road map, these
events form the core of how we work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also need help from cross project teams - the work done by them is brilliant
but it can be hard for smaller projects to consume. We have had a lot of
progress since the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/"&gt;Leveller Playing Field&lt;/a&gt; debate, but a lot of work is
still optimised for the larger teams who get direct support, or well resourced
teams who can dedicate people to the implementation of plugins / code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone I was talking to recently said - AWS is not winning public cloud
because of commodity compute (that does help - a lot), but because of the
added services that make using the cloud, well, cloud like. OpenStack needs to
decide that either it is just compute, or if it wants the eco-system. &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id10" id="id5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;
Designate is far from alone in this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to talk to anyone about helping to fill in the needed resources -
Designate is a project that started in the very office I am writing this blog
post in, and something I want to last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a visual this is Designate team in Atlanta, just before we got incubated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/ATL.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/ATL.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this was our last mid cycle:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/mid-cycle.jpg" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/mid-cycle.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and in Atlanta at the PTG, there will be two of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id6" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.openstack.org/analytics"&gt;Oct-2016&lt;/a&gt; User Survey Designate was deployed in 23% of clouds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id7" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id2"&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I have been lucky to have a management chain that is OK with me
spending some time on Designate, and have not asked me to take time off
for Summits or Gatherings, but my day job is working on a completely
different project.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id8" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id3"&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I do have other issues with the metrics - mainly that we existed before
leaving stackforge, and some of the other stats are set so
high, that non "core" projects will probably never meet them.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id9" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id4"&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I recently went to an internal training talk, where they were talking
about new features in Newton. There was a whole slide about how projects
had improved, or gotten worse on these scores. A whole slide. With
tables of scores, and I think there may have even been a graph.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id10" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/#id5"&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Now, I am slightly biased, but I would argue that DNS is needed in
commodity compute, but again, that is my view.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>designate</category><category>openstack</category><category>project update</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-designate-where-we-are/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 18:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Equal Opportunities for all OpenStack Projects</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, two weeks ago, I dropped a TC &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt; and a mailing list &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; and
waited for the other foot to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised - no one started shouting at me - but by trying
to not point fingers at individual teams I made the text too convoluted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in an effort to clarify things, here is an overview of what has been said
so far, both in the mailing list and the gerrit review itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="feedback"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
... does this also include plugins within projects, like storage
backends in cinder and hypervisor drivers in nova?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No - this was not clear enough. This change is aimed at projects that are
points of significant cross project interaction. While, in the future there may
come a point where Nova Compute Drivers are developed out of tree (though
I doubt it), that is not happening today. As a result, there is no projects in
the list of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://governance.openstack.org/reference/projects/index.html"&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; that would need to integrate with Nova.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Could you please clarify: do you advocate for a generic plugin interface for
every project, or that each project should expose a plugin interface that
allows plugin to behave as in-tree components? Because the latter is what
happens with Tempest, and I see the former a bit complicated.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every project that has cross project interaction - tempest is a good
example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these projects, they should allow all projects in tree (like Nova,
Neutron, Cinder etc are today), or they should have a plugin interface
(like they currently do), but all projects &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; use it, and not use
parts of tempest that are not exposed in that interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would mean that tempest would move the nova, neutron, etc tests to
use the plugin interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that plugin could be kept in the tempest repo, and still maintained
by the QA team, but should use the same interface as the other plugins
that are not in that repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is not just tempest - an incomplete list looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tempest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devstack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grende&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horizon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenStack SDK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searchlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistral&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celiometer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am sure I have missed some obvious ones. (if you see a project missing
let me know on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/#/c/342366/"&gt;motion&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
I think I disagree here. The root cause is being addressed: external tests can
use the Tempest plugin interface, and use the API, which is being stabilized.
The fact that the Tempest API is partially unstable is a temporary things, due
to the origin of the project and the way the scope was redefined, but again
it's temporary.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the core of a lot of the disagreement - this is only temporary,
it will all be fixed in the future, and it should stay this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the discrepancy between projects is not temporary. The specific
problems I have highlighted in the thread for one of the projects is temporary,
but I beleive the only long-term solution is to remove the difference between
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
Before we start making lots of specific rules about how teams
coordinate, I would like to understand the problem those rules are meant
to solve, so thank you for providing that example.
...
It's not clear yet whether there needs to be a new policy to change the
existing intent, or if a discussion just hasn't happened, or if someone
simply needs to edit some code.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is a big push back on editing code to help plugins from
some of the projects. Again, having the differing access between projects will
continue to exacerbate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="epigraph"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Change the name of the resolution"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—(Paraphrase from a few people)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was done in the last patchset. I think the Level Playing Field title
bounced around my head from the other resolution that was titled Level Playing
Field. It may have been confusing alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="other-areas"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Areas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I have been picking on tempest a little too much, it just captures
the current issues perfectly, and a large number of the community have some
knowledge of it, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is other areas across OpenStack the need attention as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="horizon"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Horizon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizon privileged projects have access to much more panels than
plugins (service status, quotas, overviews etc).
Plugins have to rely on tarballs of horizon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-client"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OpenStack Client&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenStack CLI privileged projects have access to more commands, as
plugins cannot hook in to them (e.g. quotas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="grenade"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Grenade&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins may or may not have tempest tests ran (I think that patch
merged), they have to use parts of tempest I was told explicitly
plugins should not use to get the tests to run at that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now add install guides and hook into the API Reference, and API
guides. This is great - and I am really happy about it. We still have
issues trying to integrate with other areas in docs, and most non docs
privileged projects end up with massive amounts of users docs in
docs.openstack.org/developer/&amp;lt;project&amp;gt; , which is not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/equal-opportunities-for-all-openstack-projects/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 21:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack - A leveler playing field</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just proposed a review to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://review.openstack.org/342366"&gt;openstack/governance&lt;/a&gt;  repo [0] that aims
to have everything across OpenStack be plugin based for all cross
project interaction, or allow all projects access to the same internal
APIs and I wanted to give a bit of background on my motivation, and how
it came about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a smaller project, I can see issues for new projects,
smaller projects, and projects that may not be seen as "important".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a smaller project trying to fit into cross project initiatives,
(and yes, make sure our software looks at least OK in the
Project Navigator) the process can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of projects / repositories have plugin interfaces, but also
have project integrations in tree, that do not follow the plugin
interface. This makes it difficult to see what a plugin can, and
should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we moved to the big tent, we wanted as a community to move to
a flatter model, removing the old integrated status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we still have areas when some projects are more equal -
there is a lingering set of projects who were integrated at the point
in time that we moved, and have preferential status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the effects are hard to see, and are not insurmountable, but
do cause projects to re-invent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, quotas - there is no way for a project that is not nova,
neutron, cinder to hook into the standard CLI, or UI for setting
quotas. They can be done as either extra commands
(openstack dns quota set --foo bar) or as custom panels, but not
the way other quotas get set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempest plugins are another example. Approximately 30 of the 36
current plugins are using resources that are not supposed to be
used, and are an unstable interface. Projects in tree in tempest
are at a much better position, as any change to the internal
API will have to be fixed before the gate merges, but other
out of tree plugins are in a place where they can be broken at any
point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is meant to single out projects, or teams. A lot
of the projects that are in this situation have inordinate amounts of
work placed on them by the big-tent, and I can emphasize with why things
are this way. These were the examples that currently stick out
in my mind, and I think we have come to a point where we need to make
a change as a community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By moving to a "plugins for all" model, these issues are reduced.
It undoubtedly will cause more, but it is closer to our goal
of Recognizing all our community is part of OpenStack, and
differentiate projects by tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This won't be a change that happens tomorrow, next week, or even next
cycle, but think as a goal, we should start moving in this direction
as soon as we can, and start building momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="note"&gt;
&lt;p class="first admonition-title"&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;This was originally posted to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lists.openstack.org/pipermail/openstack-dev/2016-July/099285.html"&gt;openstack-dev&lt;/a&gt; mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>governance</category><category>openstack</category><category>plugins</category><category>tc</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-a-leveler-playing-field/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 19:30:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>