<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>graham.hayes.ie (Posts about travel)</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://graham.hayes.ie/categories/travel.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 23:01:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Sydney OpenStack Summit</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/sydney-openstack-summit/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/9v91EBE02VNZ1fSWcd8JoH7TgPLYhSKXuKrMkqQgSwMHcsw8Im71eM01j6zolH-GuP5XqrAeq4m-GT9Yx4dZXZ_DfND-XWgqvIP64oQwQC-vZgnoLZZ3O-mnOPhQRpouOBscymYBkNelPpg5g2RRy6mXnT9e6lAVy6HGewxRRTL0VOdNApenH_zr-FeRLu_rAOs6WArITF2EbvBsXH74b3EPIGO3BeKlejiC2kSp5Xdj5u7KADXphRazHEVuB8sHegnu0CbZZ2xVLynxvgoSUBPlcwtMUhr87J8_clj0aXIksl-PAWFbhgt7xYlzBkoA1DHsDs5Vw7Cuuah-nycRYRhcSzcFIOvW7L8qWpwHXoD7Xay-DXlqfIYEZjfZc0drpV4AEAnzIaKgIa2PJsFfpiq4hqMv9T59bSIj-EX_wdQ2vXCOzokeZp2t9xCtbIeync9QR_Ij7eXJh_2XHAlLXoR7XrLsY8RiDfrmXSQWVgjEiDGd7urFn6-r3kHLj8QsYRL3ehjfr7GlMtHWuXLkadhblQYpIhnSI-aeEe6NjlXicdMKC43tpWGZkELO9Xm6I82xxycCU68q_g5Sy7BW2_BF7ERp8rNOZg2W4WFJXoySa2fsJitydiJJUvlLSnopYp5GUytsxiMie9fEXQwriFItXlFnXtZsOB8=w1440-h691-no" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/9v91EBE02VNZ1fSWcd8JoH7TgPLYhSKXuKrMkqQgSwMHcsw8Im71eM01j6zolH-GuP5XqrAeq4m-GT9Yx4dZXZ_DfND-XWgqvIP64oQwQC-vZgnoLZZ3O-mnOPhQRpouOBscymYBkNelPpg5g2RRy6mXnT9e6lAVy6HGewxRRTL0VOdNApenH_zr-FeRLu_rAOs6WArITF2EbvBsXH74b3EPIGO3BeKlejiC2kSp5Xdj5u7KADXphRazHEVuB8sHegnu0CbZZ2xVLynxvgoSUBPlcwtMUhr87J8_clj0aXIksl-PAWFbhgt7xYlzBkoA1DHsDs5Vw7Cuuah-nycRYRhcSzcFIOvW7L8qWpwHXoD7Xay-DXlqfIYEZjfZc0drpV4AEAnzIaKgIa2PJsFfpiq4hqMv9T59bSIj-EX_wdQ2vXCOzokeZp2t9xCtbIeync9QR_Ij7eXJh_2XHAlLXoR7XrLsY8RiDfrmXSQWVgjEiDGd7urFn6-r3kHLj8QsYRL3ehjfr7GlMtHWuXLkadhblQYpIhnSI-aeEe6NjlXicdMKC43tpWGZkELO9Xm6I82xxycCU68q_g5Sy7BW2_BF7ERp8rNOZg2W4WFJXoySa2fsJitydiJJUvlLSnopYp5GUytsxiMie9fEXQwriFItXlFnXtZsOB8=w1440-h691-no"&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="openstack-down-under"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OpenStack Down Under&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year the travelling circus that is the OpenStack summit migrated to
Sydney. A lot of us in Europe / North America found out exactly how far away
from our normal venues it really is. (#openstacksummit on twitter for the days
before the summit was an entertaining read :) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sunday-board-joint-leadership-meeting"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday Board / Joint Leadership Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was in Sydney, and staying across the road from the meeting, I decided to
drop in and listen. It was an interesting discussion, with a couple of
highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Dent had a very interesting item about developer satisfaction - he has
blogged about it on his blog: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://anticdent.org/openstack-developer-satisfaction.html"&gt;anticdent.org&lt;/a&gt; and it is well worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnathon Bryce lead the presentation of a proposed new expansion of the
foundation, which he touched on in the Keynote the next day - I have a few
concerns, but they are all much longer term issues, and may just be my own
interal biases. I think the first new addition to the foundation will let us
know how the rest of the process is going to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colleen Murphy and Julia Kreger told us that they (along with Flavio Percoco)
will be starting research to help improve our inclusiveness in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last item was brought forward by 2 board members, and they focused on LTS
(Long Term Support / Stable) branches. The time from an upstream release until
a user has it in production is actually long than expected - with a lot of time
being used by distros packaging and ensuring installers are up to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that by the time users have a release in production, the upstream
branches may be fully deprecated. There was a follow up Forum Session, and
there is now an effort to co-ordinate a new methodology for long term
collaboration in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/LTS-proposal"&gt;LTS Etherpad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be an assumption that distros are keeping actual git branches
around for the longer term, and not layering patches inside of deb / rpm files,
which I think is much more likely. I hope this effort succeeds, but my cynical
side thinks this is more of a "fix it for us" cry, than "help us fix it". I
suppose we will see if people show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slide from this section was not discussed but concerned me. It was talking
about having an enforced "TC Roadmap" which had lines from various workgroups
and SIGs. Coming from a project that gets a lot of "Can you do &lt;cite&gt;x&lt;/cite&gt; feature?"
(to which I usually respond with "Do you have anyone to write the code?") this
concerns me. I understand that it can be hard to get things changed in
OpenStack, really I do, but a top down enforced "Roadmap" is not the way
forward.
Honestly, that two board members of an Open Source foundation think it
is is worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="designate"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Designate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designate had 3 sessions in Sydney:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our project update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project On Boarding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ops Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project update was good - much improved from Boston, where the 2 presenters
were not paid to work on the project. We covered the major potential features,
where we were for Cycle goals (both Queens goals completed, and Pike goals
underway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project on boarding was not hugely attended, but I am hoping that was a side
effect of the summit being both smaller and far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/small_far_away.gif" src="http://graham.hayes.ie/images/small_far_away.gif"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ops feedback was great - we got a lot of bugs that were impacting our users and
deployers, and collected it in our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/SYD-forum-designate-feedback"&gt;Feedback Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; (any comments welcome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cross-project-work"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cross Project Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to quite a few cross project sessions - there was a good amount of
discussion, and some useful work came out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="application-tokens"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Application Tokens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that had completely slipped past me until now, but the ideas
were great, and it would have made things I have done in previous companies
much much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="healthchecks-per-service"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Healthchecks per service&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came to a good agreement on how we can do standardised health checks across
OpenStack, we now need to write a spec and start coding a new piece of
middleware :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="edge-computing"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Edge Computing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so sure this was worth a vist - it was much more crowded than any of the
other Forum sessions I went to, and ended up Bike Shedding on where the Edge
ends (we literally spent 10 mins talking about if a car was part of the Edge
or a thing managed by the edge.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept hearing "smaller and lighter OpenStack" in that session, but have yet
to hear what is too heavy about what we currently have. Nearly all our service
scale down to some extent, and you can run a complete infrastructure on an 8GB
VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a good summit - not too busy, and short. Looking forward to not
traveling for the next PTG, I think the DUB -&amp;gt; DOH -&amp;gt; SYD and back drained the
enthusiasm for flights for the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>tokyo</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/sydney-openstack-summit/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:35:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designate Newton Design Summit</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-newton-design-summit/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a5/Austin_Evening.jpg/1024px-Austin_Evening.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-wSSCDSC/0/X3/IMG_20160427_201746-X3.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-wSSCDSC/0/X3/IMG_20160427_201746-X3.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this on a plane on the way home from Austin, TX where we just
finished up the Newton design summit for OpenStack, and finished it a few days
later - please excuse any wierdness in syntax or flow :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austin was its usual weird, wacky, wonderful self. Everytime we are here, I
have a great time, I just can't deal with the heat :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summit format this year worked really well - I pretty much stayed in the
design summit hotel for the week - and got some very good work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="months-on-where-are-we"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6 Months On: Where are we&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I did before this design summit was to look at what we had
achived last cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a quiet cycle overall, but we did merge some vital features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operators no longer need to use the awfull config format we created for pools
in Kilo, we now have a much easier to read YAML file that is loaded into the
database via the &lt;code class="bash"&gt;designate-manage&lt;/code&gt; cli, we now actually support multiple
pools in a real way with the addition of a schedular in
&lt;code class="bash"&gt;designate-central&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-are-we-going"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where are we going?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So - the point of the design summit is to plan the future of the projects - and
designate is no execption. We were in a (very nice boardroom) room for a few
hours - and we talked through quite a few things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-p8SxMgH/0/X2/IMG_20160427_140741-X2.jpg" src="https://photos.smugmug.com/Misc/i-p8SxMgH/0/X2/IMG_20160427_140741-X2.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collection of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/newton-design-designate"&gt;etherpads&lt;/a&gt; for the summit are available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="golang-replacement-of-minidns"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Golang Replacement of MiniDNS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the nicer things about our current architecture is the flexibility that
we have because we use the standard DNS protocols to update the target DNS
servers. This has the downside however, that we are writing code that deals with
DNS packets in python, which is slow. timsim from RackSpace has writen a POC
in go that has a very large perfomance improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This needs to documented, and permission requested from the TC to move this
component to Go, (and will be a separate post in its own right).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we got back it turned out that we were not the only project considering
this, and swift actually have a feature branch with code in place. So, based on
this, we are going to collaborate with them on the integration of Go to
OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="worker-model"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Worker Model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we dicussed in Galway - we need to replace the current &lt;code class="bash"&gt;*-manager&lt;/code&gt; services
with a generic service that can scale out horizontally. As part of this we
planned out our upgrade and implementation plans for these services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="docs-deprications-and-more-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Docs, Deprications and more Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docs were a common theme - we were asked to improve them, and also have them
located in the main docs on the OpenStack.org website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a member of the docs team in the room, who gave us some great guidenance
on how to include our docs in the correct place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vmt-the-application-process"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;VMT - The application process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On of the teams that supports OpenStack is the Vunrebility Management Team.
They deal with disclosures and assigning OSSA numbers to issues that could present
and issue to our deployers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a session this summit on how that process might work, and designate
was one of the projects chosen to be used as a pilot as I have previously
produced Threat Analysis documentation for Designate inside of Hewlett Packard
Enterprise - this information is currently being processed for release to
the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="searchlight"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Searchlight&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searchlight is a new (ish) project in OpenStack that enables true searching
capabilities on clouds. We have a designate plugin, but there are issues
with how we emit notifications from the v1 and the v2 API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided that when we move the Horizon panels to v2, we will just listen for
v2 notifications in Searchlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="api-docs"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;API Docs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an interesting session on how the community are moving to document
their APIs. It will now reside in the projects repo, and is based on a
custom sphinx extention that was written for OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this progresses we will migrate designate to these docs, and remove our
current docs, as they are much harder to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>austin</category><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-newton-design-summit/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Designate Mid Cycle</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-mid-cycle/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://photos.gra.ham.ie/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-S96NrNb/0/S/IMG_3854-S.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="http://photos.gra.ham.ie/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-S96NrNb/0/O/IMG_3854.jpg" src="http://photos.gra.ham.ie/Designate-Mid-Cycle/i-S96NrNb/0/O/IMG_3854.jpg"&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="designate-mid-cycle"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Designate Mid Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a little over a week ago, and I have been trying to get my thoughts down on
paper /  rst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good few days overall - we had our usual arguements about implementation of some
familiar features, we listed out reasons that our past selves were wrong about everything,
and how we should fix our mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-mid-cycle/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (7 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>galway</category><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/designate-mid-cycle/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kosmos Mid Cycle</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/kosmos-mid-cycle/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/58/Seattle_Center_as_night_falls.jpg" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/58/Seattle_Center_as_night_falls.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/kosmos-mid-cycle/#id2" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="kosmos-mid-cycle"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kosmos Mid Cycle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat down in Seattle last week to plan out how we were going to kick start
progess on Kosmos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(For those of you who don't know what Kosmos is - here is the overview &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Kosmos"&gt;on the wiki&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided on a few things, I managed to clarify my (admitedly weird and convaluted) thought process, and we started on the inital sets of patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a small group - some people were sick from the LBaaS / VPN / FW mid cycle the week before, but enough to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We covered the DB, the layout, and how we will interact with it. I showed our basic use of the olso_versionedobjects lib, and the basic pecan framework that was in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have the basic design up on our specs repo &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/openstack/kosmos-specs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ( it is not publishing anywhere yet - I will fix that soon )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anyone is interested in the project, give me a ping - be it for developing drivers, code, requirements or general interest. (But, really - if you want to write code, just jump in, or ping me for what the hot topics are)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2 weeks time I will be off the Designate Mid Cycle - a little closer to home this time - in Galway, Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/kosmos-mid-cycle/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;By Jeffery Hayes (Jeffery Hayes) [CC BY-SA 3.0 (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0&lt;/a&gt;)], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>openstack</category><category>seattle</category><category>summit</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/kosmos-mid-cycle/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 18:14:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenStack Summit - Designate Report</title><link>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/</link><dc:creator>Graham Hayes</dc:creator><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8209/8233073411_4b2c57a36d_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/70/Ginza_at_Night,_Tokyo.jpg" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/70/Ginza_at_Night,_Tokyo.jpg"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/#id2" id="id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tokyo"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tokyo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a place. I thought I was ready for the experience, but this city has
to be visited to understand. From the 2 or 3 different metro systems that snake
across the city, to the 9 story electronics stores, it is something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in a city that has 3 metro lines that don't actually connect it was a nice
change to be able to get reliable public transport :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="design-summit"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design Summit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a much more relaxed summit for Designate. We had done a huge amount of
work in Vancouver, and we were nailing down details and doing cross project work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a few major features discussed, and laid out our priorities for the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided on the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nova / Neutron Integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pool Scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pool Configuration migration to database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IXFR (Incremental Zone Transfer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ALIAS Record type (Allows for CNAME like records at the root of a DNS Zone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DNSSEC (this may drag on for a cycle or two)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="nova-neutron-integration"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Nova &amp;amp; Neutron Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is progressing pretty well, and Miguel Lavalle has patches up for this. He,
Kiall Mac Innes and Carl Baldwin demoed this in a session on the Thursday. If
you are interested in the idea, it is definitely worth a watch &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AZbiARM9FPM"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pool-scheduler"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pool Scheduler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A vital piece of the pools re architecture that needs to be finished out.
There is no great debate on what we need, and I have taken on the task of
finishing this out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pool-configuration-migration-to-database"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pool Configuration migration to database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are current configuration file format is quite complex, and moving it to an API
allows us to iterate on it much quicker, while reducing the complexity of the
config file. I recently had to write an ansible play to write out this file, and
it was not fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiall had a patch up, so we should be able to continue based on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ixfr"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;IXFR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was quite a lot of discussion on how this will be implemented, both in the
work session, and the 1/2 day session on the Friday. Tim Simmons has stepped up,
to continue the work on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="alias"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ALIAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is quite a sort after feature - but is quite complex to implement.
The DNS RFCs explicitly ban this behavior, so we have to work the solution
around them. Eric Larson has been doing quite a lot of work on this in Liberty,
and is going to continue in Mitaka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dnssec"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a feature that we have been looking at for a while, but we started to plan
out our roadmap for it recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (I) am allergic to storing private encryption keys in Designate, so we had a
good conversation with Barbican about implementing a signing endpoint that we would
post a hash to. This work is on me to now drive for Mitaka, so we can consume it in N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some raw notes in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/mitaka-designate-summit-roadmap"&gt;etherpad&lt;/a&gt; and I expect we will soon be seeing
specs building out of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label"&gt;&lt;col&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/#id1"&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;By Francisco Diez (Flickr: Ginza at Night, Tokyo) [CC BY 2.0 (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0"&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0&lt;/a&gt;)], via Wikimedia Commons&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>openstack</category><category>summit</category><category>tokyo</category><category>travel</category><guid>http://graham.hayes.ie/posts/openstack-summit-designate-report/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 21:18:41 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>